aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
Vicious prisoners escaped from the Space Prison of Sargasso, and have begun their planetary galley.
우주 감옥 사르갓소의 흉악한 우주인들이 혹성 사냥을 개시했다
In order to protect the peace of Earth, Brave Seijin of the Space Police granted these six the brave powers of Dagwon.
지구의 평화를 지키기 위해 우주 경찰 기구의 브레이브 성인이 힘을 부여한 여섯명의 용자 다그온
And now, their new member is Gunkid!
그리고 새로운 동료는, 건키드!
Shut up!
시끄럽구만…
Who is it?
여보세요~
En! Look up the sky!
엔, 하늘을 봐라
Kai... what is it, in the morning?
카이… 아침부터 뭔 일이야?
Wake up, En!
잠 깨라, 엔!
Hurry up, come out and look up the sky!
어서 밖으로 나와서 하늘을 보…
-Sky?
-Hurry up!
-하늘?
-어서!
That's...
저건…!
Aurora...
오로라?
Maria... what is this?
누나, 이게 대체…
I think something bad is going to happen.
왠지 안좋은 예감이 들어
What a beautiful light.
예쁜 빛이구나
What's the matter, Lian?
왜그래, 라이안?
-It is same with that day.
-Huh?
-그 날과 똑같아
-에?
The morning of that day, an aurora was filling the sky.
그 날 아침도 하늘 한면에 오로라가 펼쳐져 있었어
That day?
그 날이라니?
The day my home planet Sword Planet was destroyed by Ark Seijin.
나의 고향 검성이 아크 성인에게 멸망당한 날이야
5 Minutes before the Ice Age
지구 빙하기 5분전
Space Emperor Ark Seijin
Appears
우주 황제 아크 성인
등장
Dammit! Nothing's working! Even the TV isn't working!
젠장!
틀렸어, TV도 안 나와!
Isn't an aurora supposed to happen only in polar regions?
오로라는 원래 북극이나 남극에서 생기는 거지?
It can be rarely observed in Japan too, but this time it's totally unprecedented.
일본에서도 아주 드물게 목격됩니다만 이번 같은 경우는 전대 미문입니다
Isn't it alright?
뭐 어때?
Talking about love, looking at the aurora!
오로라를 보면서 사랑을 나눈다던가~
Shin!
신!
It's a total disaster in hospitals! Medical appliances ceased to work!
병원에선 의료기기가 정지해서 큰일이 났단 말이야!
Moreover, because of the magnetic storm that the aurora came with, the city ceased to work.
게다가 오로라가 동반하는 강한 자기 폭풍(磁氣嵐) 때문에 도시 기능은 마비 상태야
I didn't know.
그랬구만요…
Would it be a natural phenomenon, or...
자연 현상까요, 아니면…
You know, it's cold here.
근데, 어째 추운걸
Isn't the air conditioner working too strongly in this room?
이 방, 냉방이 너무 심한 거 아니야?
Nonsense. There's no cooler in this room.
그럴 리 없잖아
여긴 에어컨도 없다구
Oh, is that so?
아앗! 그런가?
Big problem! Snow! It's snowing!
큰일이야!
눈이야! 눈이 내린다구!
What?!
뭐라고?!
I have no doubts. Only one guy can do this. Ark Seijin, that is.
틀림없어, 이건 녀석…
아크 성인의 짓이야
Huh? Then...
에에? 그럼…
Right. He is trying to freeze the Earth up this time.
그래, 녀석은 이번엔 이 지구를 얼려버릴 셈이야
No way!
그럴수가!
Of course, that will not happen.
물론, 그렇게 되도록 내버려두진 않아
I will stop him no matter what.
내가 반드시 막아 보이겠어
I'll go too!
나도 갈 거야!
You shouldn't come! Ark Seijin is my enemy! I'll defeat him myself.
너는 오지마!
아크 성인은 내 적이야 나 혼자서 쓰러뜨리겠어
Lian...
라이안…
Wait here.
여기서 기다리고 있어
Lian!
라이아~안!
Lian...
라이안…
He shouldn't be far away from here.
녀석은 분명 그리 멀지 않은 곳에 있을 터다
He must be expecting that I'll act right away as soon as I see the aurora.
오로라를 보면 내가 바로 행동에 들어갈 것도 예상하고 있을 거야
Where is it? Where are you, Ark Seijin?!
어디냐!
어디 있느냐, 아크 성인?!
I never thought I would have to wear an overcoat in this season.
이 계절에 오버를 입게 될 거라곤 생각 못 했어
It's getting colder and colder.
점점 추워져
The magnetic field here is more dispersed than everywhere else.
이 근방의 자기(磁氣)가 특별히 흐트러져 있어
You appeared, Ark Seijin!
나타났구나, 아크 성인!
The Earth is all over.
지구는 이제 끝장이다
What?!
뭐야?!
It's snowing a lot outside!
밖은 벌써 펑펑 내리는구만
This is impossible!
이런 현상, 있을 수 없어요!
Damn... It is obvious that an alien did this!
젠장… 이건 틀림없이 우주인의 짓이야!
A sudden decline in temperature...
급격한 기온의 저하…
Any suspects?
너희들, 짐작 가는 거 없어?
Suspect?
짐작 가는 거?
Ark Seijin annihilated Sword Planet of Lian by suddenly bringing an ice age.
라이안이 있던 검성을 아크 성인은 순식간에 빙하기로 만들어서 전멸시켰어
Then... it can't be!
그렇다면, 설마…!
Are you trying to make Earth like Sword Planet?!
설마 네녀석, 지구를 검성처럼 만들 셈이냐?!
Dear native of Sword Planet, if you value your life, you'd better run away to Space right now.
검성인이여, 목숨이 아깝다면 이틈에 우주로 도망치거라
Do not mock me!
날 우롱하지 마라!
I will send you to hell right now!
지금이야말로 네놈을 지옥으로 보내 주마!
To take revenge for the 2 billion lives!
검성인 20억의 원수를 갚기 위해서
And to save the earthlings!
그리고 지구 인류를 구하기 위해서!
To save the earthlings? This is surprising.
지구 인류를 구하기 위해? 이거 놀랍군
Do you like earthlings to that extent?
그렇게까지 지구인이 마음에 들었나?
You're not the Lian of solitude I knew.
그 고독한 라이안이…
Shut up! I will not let you do as you want anymore!
닥쳐! 이 이상 멋대로 하게 두진 않는다!
Do you really think you can defeat me?
정말 날 이길 수 있다고 생각하나?
-I do not need to win the match.
-What?
-승부에서 이길 필요 따윈 없다
-뭐야?
Did you forget? I have an antimatter reactor in my body.
잊었나? 내 몸에는 반물질 반응로가 있다
I will blow myself up, and take you with me!
네놈을 길동무로 난 자폭할 것이다!
How foolish!
어리석은…!
Don't do it!
그만둬!
Gunkid!
건키드!
Don't do this, Lian!
그만둬, 라이안!
I told you not to follow!
따라오지 말랬잖아!
Lian! I don't want you to die!
라이안! 죽으면 안돼!
Go back! This is my battle!
돌아가! 이건 내 싸움이야!
I will fight too!
나도 싸울 거야!
Let's take down Ark Seijin together!
나도 같이 아크 성인을 쓰러뜨릴 거야!
So Lian, don't die! You must not die!
그러니까 라이안, 죽지마!
죽으면 안돼!
Gunkid, you...
건키드, 너…
No matter how many crawl up, it won't work to me!
몇 놈이 기어오든, 내겐 통하지 않는다!
What?!
아니?!
Farewell, Ken Seijin!
작별이다, 검성인!
Go to the other world with your android!
안드로이드와 함께 저세상으로 가거라!
What is that light?
뭐지, 저 빛은?
Let's go out!
출동하자!
Right. We must find his Ark Castle using any method possible.
그래, 어떻게 해서든 녀석의…
아크 성을 찾아내야만 해
Alright!
좋았어!
Everyone!
얘들아
Ryu, what is it?
류, 무슨 일이야?
I just observed an unknown explosion.
지금 의문의 폭발을 목격했어
I'll head to the scene.
지금부터 현장으로 향할 거야
Understood. We'll join you soon.
알았어, 우리도 곧 합류할게
It's Dagwon! Dagwon is flying!
다그온이다!
다그온이 날아가고 있어!
Maria, take a look!
누나, 가 보자!
Ryu!
류!
What the hell is this?
이건 대체…
Everything froze up at once after the explosion a moment ago.
좀전의 폭발로 순식간에 얼어붙은 것 같아
The whole city is like a big fridge!
마을 전체가 마치 거대한 냉장고 같구만
It must be caused by an extremely low temperature that exceeds Liner Blizzard by far.
아마 라이너 블리자드를 월등히 상회하는 초저온의 짓일 겁니다
I see.
그렇군…
-Ark Castle?
-That bastard!
-아크 성?!
-이자식!
I hope you liked my present, Dagwon gentlemen.
내 선물은 마음에 들었나
다그온 제군
Y-you punk!
이, 이자식…!
I just turned on the switch of the planet freezing device.
방금 전에 혹성 동결 장치의 스위치를 작동시켰다
What did you say?!
뭐라고?!
Then, the white light moments ago must be...!
그럼, 좀전의 하얀 빛이?!
That's right.
그 말대로다
This castle itself is a gigantic planet freezing device.
이 성 자체가 거대한 혹성 동결 장치다
And after 30 minutes,
그리고 앞으로 30분 후면
the Earth will rush into an unprecedentedly immense Ice Age.
지구는 전례 없는 규모의 대 빙하기에 돌입할 것이다
Immense Ice Age?!
대 빙하기?!
Just like Sword Planet, the Earth will become a dark and cold planet of death.
검성과 마찬가지로 지구는 어둡고 차가운 죽음의 별이 되는 거다
-That's impossible!
-You are Death!
-말도 안돼!
-네놈은 사신이야!
Say whatever you want.
뭐라고 지껄이든 상관없다
You earthlings will disappear in this Space for eternity after 30 minutes!
너희들 지구인은 30분 후에는 이 우주에서 영원히 소멸할 것이다
Don't make us laugh! The Earth has us.
웃기지마!
지구에는 우리가 있다!
Dagwon will protect the Earth!
다그온이 지구를 지킬 거야!
How futile. How worthless.
소용 없다
Your power is just like a baby to me.
너희들의 힘 따윈 내 앞에선 갓난아기나 마찬가지
Look at this!
이걸 보거라!
-Lian!
-Gunkid!
-라이안!
-건키드!
No way... this can't be...
이런… 이럴수가…
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
This is the biggest crisis that humankind has ever faced.
이건 우리 인류가 맞이하는 최대의 위기야
Damn, we only have 30 minutes!
젠장, 앞으로 30분 밖에 없다니!
No, we still have 30 minutes!
아니, 아직 30분이나 있어!
En!
엔!
I will act!
난 싫다구!
Are we going to be killed by Ark Seijin doing nothing?
이대로 아크 성인에게 죽을 순 없어!
Yes. En is right.
음, 엔의 말대로야
We'll absolutely destroy that castle and stop the activity of that device!
저 성을 파괴해서 장치의 활동을 반드시 정지시켜야 해!
-Everyone! Combine!
-Yeah!
-얘들아, 합체다!
-오우!
Look at that, Maria!
저걸 봐, 누나!
Dagwon is...
다그온이…
Jet Fire Storm!
제트 파이어 스톰!
Shadow Cannon!
섀도우 캐논!
Super Liner Crush!
슈퍼 라이너 크러시!
No, it isn't working!
틀렸어, 통하질 않아!
Dagwon!
다그온!
I'll be observing the last moments of Earth in the upper atmosphere.
난 상공에서 지구의 최후를 지켜보마
Farewell, Dagwon gentlemen!
안녕이다, 다그온 제군!
Ark Seijin!
아크 성인!
You're not getting away!
놓칠까보냐!
En!
엔!
-Lian!
-You were alive!
-라이안!
-살아있었구나!
Yeah, thanks to Gunkid.
아아, 건키드 덕분이야
He released the energy of his internal battery to heat me up.
저녀석은 자신의 체내 전지를 방열(放熱)해서 날 데워주고 있었어
I see.
그랬구나…
Gunkid, you...
건키드, 너…!
We have no more time!
더 이상 시간이 없어!
We must do something to destroy Ark Castle!
어서 아크 성을 파괴해야 해!
But Gunkid won't be able to shoot the Infinity Cannon for now!
하지만 지금의 건키드에게 무한포의 발사는 무리야
We have one measure left.
단 하나, 방법이 있어
That is...
그건…
The Dag Vehicles.
다그 비클이야
The Dag Vehicles?
다그 비클?
Right. We will supply our energy to Gunkid.
그래, 우리 머신의 에너지를 모두 건키드에게 주는 거야
If we do that, we won't be able to perform Merging Fusion.
그런 짓을 했다간, 우리는 융합합체조차 할 수 없게 돼
Now, we only can bet on the Infinity Cannon!
이젠 무한포에 걸 수밖에 없어!
There's no other measure left!
달리 남은 방법이 없잖아!
Ark Seijin!
아크 성인!
Good job coming here, Dag Fire.
용케 여기까지 왔구나
다그 파이어
Stop the device!
장치를 멈춰!
I am the Space Emperor.
나는 우주 황제다
I have the right to rule all the stars and planets.
나는 모든 별을 지배할 권리가 있단 말이다
And...
그리고…
the right to bring a downfall to a planet where only inferior life forms exists.
하등한 생물만이 살고 있는 별을 멸망시킬 권리도 말이지
You bastard!
이자식!
It was really fun fighting with you guys.
너희들과의 싸움은 정말 즐거웠다
I have always appreciated all your efforts. Thank you.
감사하고 있다, 고맙다
Shut up!
닥쳐!
What?!
아니?!
-Are you alright?
-Lian! Gunkid!
-괜찮아?
-라이안! 건키드!
Were you alright?
무사했어?!
En. Let me destroy the Ark Castle with my Infinity Cannon!
무한포로 아크 성을 없애 버리자!
Right. That's a good idea!
그래, 그 방법이 있었군!
Blazing Fusion!
화염합체
(火炎合體)
Fire Dagwon!
파이어 다그온
We must win with one shot! Approach the enemy!
일발 승부다!
가능한 한 접근하자!
Infinity Cannon!
무한포!
Everyone's energy!
모두가 준 에너지다!
Fire!
발사(FIRE)!
En! Hang in there!
엔, 정신차려!
Kai... what about the Ark Castle?
카이… 아크 성은?!
What?
뭐라고?!
We only have five minutes left!
앞으로 5분 밖에 안 남았어!
Has the Earth come to an end?
지구는 이제 끝장인가?!
You idiot!
바보 자식!
I'll go!
내가 가겠다!
I will release my antimatter reactor!
반물질 반응로를 개방하마!
No, I'll go!
아니, 가는 건 나다!
Lian!
라이안!
You keep that bomb until the moment of Ark Seijin's defeat!
그 폭탄은 아크 성인을 쓰러뜨릴 때까지 간직하고 있어!
En...
엔…
En! What are you going to do?!
엔! 무슨 짓을 할 셈이야?!
I'm counting on you, Fire Jumbo!
부탁한다, 파이어 점보!
En.
엔…
The crisis of Earth is over now.
지구의 위기는 끝났다…
En.
엔…
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
tooku kirameita
kaze no naka no PRISM
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
Losing Fire Jumbo does not mean I have to be sad!
파이어 점보를 읺었지만 슬퍼하고 있을 순 없겠지?
That's right. After all, there's always a queen ant in an ant colony.
그 말대로입니다 개미 집단에는 반드시 여왕 개미가 있으니까요
-Hey, what do you mean?
-Zargoss Seijin's lady,
-여봐, 뭔 소리냐?
-자고스 성인의 여왕
Queen Zargoss finally came to fight!
퀸 자고스가 마침내 싸움을 걸어 왔어요!
She is a powerful enemy! Leave her to me!
이녀석은 강적이다! 내게 맡겨라!
-You can't become Fire Dagwon!
-I'll still fight!
-파이어 다그온이 될 수 없는데요?
-그래도 싸울 거라구!
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! Super Strength! Power Dagwon
다음회 용자지령 다그온
강력! 파워 다그온
Feast your eyes on the power up that will make you go "Wow!"
앗! 하고 놀랄 파워 업! 잘 보라구!
Super Strength! Power Dagwon
강력! 파워 다그온